<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<process version="4.4">

  <operator name="Root" class="Process" expanded="yes">
      <description text="#ylt#p#ygt#You have loaded the simplest possible RapidMiner process. Actually, it does not perform anything.#ylt#/p#ygt##ylt#table#ygt##ylt#tr#ygt##ylt#td#ygt##ylt#icon#ygt#operators/24/chain#ylt#/icon#ygt##ylt#/td#ygt##ylt#td#ygt##ylt#p#ygt#Please click on the operator named #yquot#Root#yquot# in the tree view. This is the root operator of a very simple operator tree without any children. On the right side the global process parameters can be changed.#ylt#/p#ygt##ylt#/td#ygt##ylt#/tr#ygt##ylt#tr#ygt##ylt#td#ygt##ylt#/td#ygt##ylt#td#ygt##ylt#p#ygt#Two basic perspectives (or view modes) are available in RapidMiner: first, the edit mode displaying the operator tree, the parameters, and all tools necessary for the design of processes. Second, the results view showing the (intermediate) results of the current process. They will be shown after the process is finished.#ylt#/p#ygt##ylt#/td#ygt##ylt#/tr#ygt##ylt#tr#ygt##ylt#td#ygt##ylt#icon#ygt#24/edit#ylt#/icon#ygt##ylt#/td#ygt##ylt#td#ygt##ylt#i#ygt#You can switch into the edit mode by pressing this button located in the right corner of the toolbar.#ylt#/i#ygt##ylt#/td#ygt##ylt#/tr#ygt##ylt#tr#ygt##ylt#td#ygt##ylt#icon#ygt#24/presentation_chart#ylt#/icon#ygt##ylt#/td#ygt##ylt#td#ygt##ylt#i#ygt#The result mode is activated by pressing this button. The result viewer is automatically activated at the end of a process#ylt#/i#ygt##ylt#/td#ygt##ylt#/tr#ygt##ylt#/table#ygt##ylt#p#ygt#Please try out the following:  #ylt#ul#ygt##ylt#li#ygt#Change back to #yquot#Tree#yquot# view. Right click on the root operator. A context menu allows some actions. Try to add another operator. You have to select the menu item #yquot#New operator#yquot# and an operator of one of the subgroups. Short informations about the operators are displayed in the tool tip text. Please note that new operators can only be added to operator chains. #ylt#table#ygt##ylt#tr#ygt##ylt#td#ygt##ylt#icon#ygt#24/element_new#ylt#/icon#ygt##ylt#/td#ygt##ylt#td#ygt##ylt#i#ygt#Select an operator from one of the #yquot#New operator#yquot# subgroups in the context menu of a selected operator chain#ylt#/i#ygt##ylt#/td#ygt##ylt#/tr#ygt##ylt#/table#ygt##ylt#/li#ygt##ylt#li#ygt#After adding one or several arbitrary operators click on the #yquot#Validate process#yquot# icon in the icon bar (the one on the right with the check mark). Maybe some error messages are produced and displayed in the message viewer at the bottom of the screen. In the next steps we will see how valid processes can be created. #ylt#table#ygt##ylt#tr#ygt##ylt#td#ygt##ylt#icon#ygt#24/checks#ylt#/icon#ygt##ylt#/td#ygt##ylt#td#ygt##ylt#i#ygt#Validate process setup#ylt#/i#ygt##ylt#/td#ygt##ylt#/tr#ygt##ylt#/table#ygt##ylt#/li#ygt##ylt#/ul#ygt#When you have finished you can proceed to the next process.  #ylt#/p#ygt#"/>
      <parameter key="logverbosity"	value="init"/>
      <parameter key="random_seed"	value="2001"/>
      <parameter key="encoding"	value="SYSTEM"/>
  </operator>

</process>
